Hello, my friends.
And welcome to exercise number 25.
We are going to explain the functionality of the following function this is function number two.
It took in the parameter int and and it returns integer it checks.
If an equal equal to one, it will return zero.
Otherwise, it will return one plus function to and passing the parameter and over to both the video.
And think about this question.
Please write it down on your copy.
Book and write the solution in the comments below.
In order to make a discussion and see what the points and what are the vulnerabilities in understanding
the data structure and algorithms, of course.
OK, so waiting your answers here we have the function I told you to take an example, always take an
example and or your interviews and in their exercises, so I will take an int.
And equal to four.
OK, so I will take take an equal to four.
OK, so.
I gather.
Execute function two of four.
What does this mean?
Function of four.
Any four to four?
Is it equal, equal to one?
No.
So that it will skip the the Alice comes.
Else it will return.
This will return one plus function to.
And mine and over two so and over two for over two is to this will called a recursive function to.
Do and function to of two.
This is.
Going to occur again.
To equal if an equal equal to one no and equal to two.
Else return one.
Plus function two off and equal to one SRT and equal to two two over two is equal to one.
Again, this will be function to.
Of one is equal to an equal, equal to one.
Yes, so return here.
So this zero will go up and being substituted with function two of one.
So this would be remote because it is if to two zero one plus zero is equal to one f of two is one.
So it is being replaced here and return one plus function of two, which is equal one plus one.
And this word return sorry, one plus one here.
So this function were returned one plus one, which is if was to do so, the final answer of this function
of four is equal to two.
OK.
This is how we solve that questions again.
I will take an example and show you how this works.
OK.
I will take an example of half of five, OK?
F of five.
And equal to five is not equal to one.
So this skipped the part F.
Else return, this will return one plus.
Function of.
Five over to function.
Off and over two and as being an end, so five over two were resolved and 2.5, but it is since it is
an integer and it was removed, I removed the decimal part and it well, it well.
Like return just to only the integer part, so f 2.5 and over two is five over two, which is two point
five, where we remove the 0.5 and we keep on two.
OK.
Function F of two is equal to return since and is not equal to one and is equal to two here, so it
will return one plus function off and which is two over two is equal to one.
So again, out of one.
And equal to one.
Yes, so it will return zero, so if one is equal to zero, it's going up and we replace it with a return
one plus zero.
OK.
This will return one.
So f of two is equal to one.
It's going out here and f of two as equal to one.
And if f of five is returning, one plus one is equal to two.
OK?
This is the same as f of this happens because we are dealing with integer and we have removed two point
five.
We have removed the zero point five from the decimal part and we keep on the integer part.
This is the way how recursion works, and you are asked how to explain the functionality, explaining
the functionality of the recursion.
And I need from you to take this example and try to solve like f of six, f of 10 and C.